MATTHEW OLADELE

2X Salesforce Certified | 9X Salesforce Superbadges

+1 (317) 665 5829

0

Indianapolis, Indiana

ABOUT

A Salesforce Certified Platform Developer and Platform App Builder, with 9X Superbadges and over 13 years of professional experience. Passionate about using technology and creative skills to solve problems. A graduate of both the web development program at Eleven Fifty Academy and the Salesforce Pathfinder and Deloitte Training Program with a bachelors degree in Graphic Design.

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

- Portfolio https://oladelematthew.github.io/oladelematthew-github.io
- Github https://aithub.com/oladelematthew
- LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-oladele

SKILLS

- Proficient in Salesforce Process Automation and Logic (Constructs in Apex, SOQL, SOSL, and DML, Apex Classes and Triggers), User Interface (Visualforce and Lightning Component Framework), Testing, Debugging and Deployment, Database Modeling and Management, Salesforce Fundamentals
- Proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript, JSON, REST API's, React, Express.js and Typescript
- Proficient in Run Time Environments (Node.js) and Databases (PostgreSQL, MySQL)
- Proficient in Wordpress and Beaver Builder
- Proficient in Microsoft Office Word, Powerpoint and Excel
- Proficient in Adobe Creative Suite

EDUCATION

Salesforce and Deloitte Pathfinder Program | June 2020 - August 2020 Salesforce Certified Platform Developer | | February 2021

• Certified Platform Developer I (PDI) developers understand how to develop and deploy custom business logic and custom interfaces using the programmatic capabilities of the Lightning Platform. They know when to use declarative versus programmatic methods, and can extend the Lightning Platform using Apex and Visualforce.

Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder | March 2021

• Certified Platform App Builders have the skills and knowledge to design, build, and implement custom applications using the declarative customization capabilities of the Salesforce Platform.

Eleven Fifty Academy (Indianapolis, IN) | February 2020 - July 2020 Web Development Certification

- Relevant coursework: APIs, DOM, Firebase Deployment, Heroku Deployment, Introduction to Ui, CSS, Express, GIT, GitHub, HTML, Javascript, Node, PostgreSQL, React, Sequelize
- Related Projects: Utilized HTML, CSS, bootstrap, Formspree and Javascript to build a
 personal portfolio. Also created a React App using React framework, React Libraries
 and Node.js

Federal University of Technology (Ondo, Nigeria) | December 2003 - September 2008 Bachelor Degree in Graphic Design

GPA: 3.58

- Relevant coursework: Photography, Illustration, Color Theory, Screen printing, Freehand Drawing, 3D Modelling, Printing, Advertising, Publishing and Book Design, Typography
- Related Projects: Digital Wall Branding of The ETF building of the university

WORK EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE SALESFORCE DEVELOPER | February 2021 - Present More Time Club - Indianapolis, IN

Leverage the power of Salesforce customizations to develop scalable and adaptive solutions for B2B with a focus on helping businesses grow through practical and affordable business solutions.

WEB DEVELOPER (Volunteer) | September 2020 - Present **American Youth Literacy Foundation**

- Work with a team of developers to develop and maintain FUNetix website
- Gather and refine specifications based on technical needs
- Make weekly updates to the web pages, adding relevant keywords for SEO optimization

SALESFORCE DEVELOPER | April 2021 - July 2021 b atomic IIc

Core: develop, integrate, and consult on the b atomic products

- · Worked directly with clients on product development and custom functionality
- Developed and integrated additional Salesforce functionality into core products
- Worked with third party engineering and development teams
- Operated primarily inside Salesforce CRM
- Supported additional product design

WEB DEVELOPER | February 2020 - July 2020

Premier Commercial Service - Indianapolis, IN

- Collaborated with other developers (using github) to build full-stack applications
- Worked with Trello app to plan, document and analyze project developments
- Worked with postman and pgAdmin to test every level of project development before deployment using heroku app

PROJECTS

Neon Support (SFDX Project for b atomic IIc)

- https://github.com/oladelematthew/neon-support
- Custom App for Neon Product Support

Personal Portfolio

- https://oladelematthew.github.io/oladelematthew-github.io
- Utilized HTML, CSS, bootstrap, Formspree and JavaScript

React App - taskPriority

- https://om-taskpriority.herokuapp.com
- Frontend was built with React and backend in Node.js

Premier Commercial Service

- https://premier-client.herokuapp.com
- Frontend was built with typescript and backend in Node.js